<!-- Copyright (C) The IETF Trust (2008-2012) -->

<t>
<list style="hanging">

<t hangText="Administrator:"> A user with the necessary authority to
    initiate administrative tasks on one or more servers.  </t>

<t hangText="Admin Entity:"> A server or agent that administers a
    collection of fileservers and persistently stores the namespace
    information.  </t>

<t hangText="Client:"> Any client that accesses fileserver data
    using a supported file-access protocol.  </t>

<t hangText="Federation:"> A set of server collections and singleton
    servers that use a common set of interfaces and protocols in order
    to provide to their clients a federated namespace accessible
    through a filesystem access protocol.  </t>

<t hangText="Fileserver:"> A server exporting one or more filesystems
    via a file-access protocol.  </t>

<t hangText="Fileset:"> The abstraction of a set of files and the
    directory tree that contains them. A fileset is the 
    fundamental unit of data management in the federation.

    <vspace blankLines="1" />

    Note that all files within a fileset are descendants of one
    directory, and that filesets do not span filesystems.  </t>

<t hangText="Filesystem:"> A self-contained unit of export for a
    fileserver, and the mechanism used to implement filesets.  The
    fileset does not need to be rooted at the root of the filesystem,
    nor at the export point for the filesystem.

    <vspace blankLines="1" />

    A single filesystem MAY implement more than one fileset, if the
    client protocol and the fileserver permit this. </t>

<t hangText="File-access Protocol:"> A network filesystem access
    protocol such as NFSv3 <xref
    target="RFC1813"/>, NFSv4 <xref target="3530bis"/>, or
    CIFS (Common Internet File System) <xref target="MS-SMB"/> 
    <xref target="MS-SMB2"/> <xref target="MS-CIFS"/>.  </t>

<t hangText="FSL (Fileset Location):"> The location of the
    implementation of a fileset at a particular moment in time.  An FSL
    MUST be something that can be translated into a protocol-specific
    description of a resource that a client can access directly, such
    as an fs_location (for NFSv4), or share name (for CIFS).  Note that
    not all FSLs need to be explicitly exported as long as they are
    contained within an exported path on the fileserver.  </t>

<t hangText="FSN (Fileset Name):"> A platform-independent and globally
    unique name for a fileset.  Two FSLs that implement replicas of
    the same fileset MUST have the same FSN, and if a fileset is
    migrated from one location to another, the FSN of that fileset
    MUST remain the same.  </t>

<t hangText="Junction:"> A filesystem object used to link a directory
    name in the current fileset with an object within another fileset. 
    The server-side "link" from a leaf node in one fileset to the root
    of another fileset.  </t>

<t hangText="Namespace:"> A filename/directory tree that a
    sufficiently authorized client can observe.  </t>

<t hangText="NSDB (Namespace Database) Service:"> A service that maps
    FSNs to FSLs.  The NSDB may also be used to store other
    information, such as annotations for these mappings and their
    components.  </t>

<t hangText="NSDB Node:"> The name or location of a server that
    implements part of the NSDB service and is responsible for keeping
    track of the FSLs (and related info) that implement a given
    partition of the FSNs.  </t>

<t hangText="Referral:"> A server response to a client access that
    directs the client to evaluate the current object as a reference
    to an object at a different location (specified by an FSL) in
    another fileset, and possibly hosted on another fileserver.  The
    client re-attempts the access to the object at the new location. 
    </t>

<t hangText="Replica:"> A replica is a redundant implementation of a
    fileset.  Each replica shares the same FSN, but has a different
    FSL.

    <vspace blankLines="1" />

    Replicas may be used to increase availability or performance. 
    Updates to replicas of the same fileset MUST appear to occur in
    the same order, and therefore each replica is self-consistent at
    any moment.

    <vspace blankLines="1" />

    We do not assume that updates to each replica occur simultaneously.
    If a replica is offline or unreachable, the other replicas may be
    updated.  </t>

<t hangText="Server Collection:"> A set of fileservers administered as
    a unit.  A server collection may be administered with
    vendor-specific software.

    <vspace blankLines="1" />

    The namespace provided by a server collection could be part of the
    federated namespace.  </t>

<t hangText="Singleton Server:">  A server collection containing only one server; a
    stand-alone fileserver.  </t>

</list>
</t>
